you've gone mega viral on Tik Tok, on
Instagram, just in like
overnight almost uh I would say like in
the last couple weeks. It's kind of
amazing.
>> Uh it's mostly among Gen Z, so people my
age and they have a particular interest
in what you have to say. I'm wondering
why you think that is.
>> I'm thrilled by that. You know, I've
actually asked a couple people uh why
that is because I'm not entirely sure
myself and and a couple have just
without skipping a beat come right out
and said it's because you tell the truth
and that there was a price that came
with telling the truth and people
respect that which makes me
makes me very very happy. Um,
maybe on a less serious note
is that I'm kind of proud at my
storytelling
abilities.
And it might be that, you know, I'm a
I'm a good storyteller and some of them
are fun and, you know, they they cut
them and make lasers shoot out of my
eyes and, you know, give me the Alvin
and the Chipmunk's voice. I I don't know
if that's it or not. And I think on a
more serious note, it's it's that I I
have consistently told the truth. You
know, I remember I remember making a
decision in December of um 2007 when I
was getting ready to go on that Brian
Ross interview on ABC News. And I
decided, and I even said this to my wife
at the time, I'm going to tell the truth
no matter what he asks me and just let
the cards fall. And then um and then
fast forwarding
another well exactly seven years like to
the week um I was
I was six six weeks before being
released from prison. I was able to call
my my wife every other day for 15
minutes. And I called her one day in
December of 2014 and I said, "How was
your day?" She said, "It was great." And
I said, "Really? What made it so great?"
and she said because the Senate torture
report was released today and it proved
that everything you said was true. And
so, you know, it's
there's just no better policy than to
tell the truth. People will recognize
that you're telling the truth and
they'll respect you for it. And I think
that's why it's it's taken off. Now,
that's that's in the most recent
example. Earlier on, you know, I I I was
on Tucker Carlson's show. Oh, I'm gonna
say it was in the spring. No, we're in
the spring. So, it was it was probably
in the fall of last year. And then I did
Patrick Bet David. And then I did Joe
Rogan. And then I did Diary of a CEO.
And each one of those shows built on the
previous ones. And so it gave me
exposure to people who otherwise had
never heard of me, young people who were
too young at the time of my
whistleblowing. And so it's kind of like
this new generation of people that's
just discovered my message and I think
that's been a very positive thing as
well.
>> I I completely agree and just as someone
who is Gen Z, uh I could just say this
generation uh they don't believe
anything that the federal government
>> tells them about our foreign policy,
about all the wars that we're fighting,
usually on behalf of Israel. Um they
call it fed slop in fact that you know
like slop that the federal government is
feeding them.
>> Oh that's a great term fed slop. I
hadn't heard of it.
>> And and you're famous of course for kind
of debunking fed slop. you know, when it
comes to this torture report um or or
when it came to our global torture and
rendition program, as we saw in the
torture report, the CIA had offices
devoted to spreading lies about that
program, saying that it was successful
and giving us results and you of course
exposed all this.
>> I I want to move on uh to another reason
why I think people are so interested in
what you have to say now. I think it has
to do with what we're seeing play out in
Congress uh and the White House over
these Epstein files. Yeah.
>> To the point where government secrecy
and deep state redactions have just
basically become a meme. Um, when it
comes to what limited files that have
been released, there is a lot that I
want to ask you about. I do want to
start with someone who has gotten in
trouble for her ties to Epstein, which
is Kathy Rumler. Yes.
>> Who was the former White House chief
legal counsel under Obama. It was
revealed in these emails her extensive
connections to the US deep state, even
winning this CIA award personally from
John Brennan, the director,
>> which may I add,
>> is normally given to people who are
killed in the line of duty.
[snorts]
>> It's very interesting. I, you know, I I
haven't seen this award either just
given to a civilian um winning these
types of CIA awards. What does that tell
us then about the ties between not you
know the CIA and and Wall Street where
she worked but also just who she was and
what she may have been doing that she
the civilian is winning CIA awards.
>> Yeah. I'm going to I'm going to
speculate here too because I think that
this is a very important story that's
not being covered. Um Kathy Rumler was
the White House counsel under Barack
Obama, the seniormost attorney in the
White House.
Why did she have such a close and
abiding relationship with John Brennan?
I mean, we can speculate as to why she
had such a close and abiding
relationship with Jeffrey Jeffrey
Epstein. And and you will have seen by
now the the numerous emails that she
sent Epstein saying, "When are you in
town again?" "Oh, next week. I want us
to get together with John Brennan. Are
you free? Oh, you're gonna love John
Brennan. We should get together for
dinner. Oh, let me introduce you to John
Brennan. He's a real sweetheart.
Why? Why was there this overwhelming
desire to introduce Jeffrey Epstein to
John Brennan? And why did Kathy Rumler
have this relationship with John
Brennan? So, here's my speculation. Um,
in in 2009,
The New Yorker magazine broke a major
story in that they reported on the
existence of what was then called the
Tuesday morning kill list meeting.
Right? This is a meeting at the White
House chaired by John Brennan, who at
the time was the deputy national
security adviser for counterterrorism.
They would come up with a list of people
to be killed that week by the CIA,
people who had not been charged with
crimes, people who had not faced their
accusers in a court of law. The teams
would fan out around the world, they
would kill their targets, and then they
would go back to the White House the
next Tuesday and get their list from
that Tuesday morning kill list meeting.
Well, John Brennan was chairing that.
Kathy Rumler
would have been the final legal
authority in the White House to approve
those assassinations.
And I think she was into it and I think
that's why they became friends. Now, she
was in over her head with with Epstein.
I mean, I can't imagine that somebody so
smart could be so stupid, but you know,
here we are. And I'm wondering if
I'm wondering if it was Epstein that
wanted her to to broker this
introduction to John Brennan. Now, we
also know from this latest trunch of
Epstein files that
that Epstein's attorneys reached out to
the CIA and to the NSC
and asked for some sort of a letter,
some sort of documentation
proving that Epstein had ties to the
CIA. We we don't know that he did. I
think he did. My belief is that he did.
even if they were incidental, even if
they were, um, oh, what's the word? Um,
transa, excuse me, transactional.
And so, um,
I'd like to now know what the story is
about John Brennan. And God knows he
hasn't said anything at all about
Jeffrey Epstein.
>> There's a story here.
>> John Brennan uh, has always been one of
the most mysterious deep state creatures
in Washington. He's someone that you
know very intimately from your time
working at the bin Laden station. He
was, I believe, the head of uh Saudi
Arabia station at the time in the 1990s.
Um, and he's just been endlessly
promoted despite overseeing a really a
series of security failures in the
United States, including, I would say,
911. Can you talk about
>> how you know him and your experience
working with him and and why you think
he's just uh ascended uh so quickly? uh
up the deep state ladder.
>> This this is very very much
a a Washington swamp creature story.
Uh when I first met John, he was the
deputy chief of the Arab-Israeli
analysis group,
a mid-level nobody.
So,
he was a GS-15, a a relatively new
GS-15, and he was working for a woman
named Martha Kesler.
Now, Martha was arguably the US
government's leading or one of the US
government's leading experts on Syria.
She was brilliant and she was elegant.
and he went to Martha in the mid1 1990s
at Christmas time and he said,"Martha,
I've been your deputy for three years
now and I think that I am ready for
promotion into the senior intelligence
service and I want your blessing." And
she said,
"Not only will you never be promoted
into the foreign int the senior
intelligence service, I don't even want
you working for me anymore. You're
fired."
Well, at the CIA, when you're fired,
quote unquote fired, you're not really
fired so much as you are given six weeks
to find another job. And if you can't
find a job in six weeks, then you're
fired and they escort you to your car
and they take your badge and nobody ever
hears from you again.
So, the normal turnover period for jobs
is in the summertime. This was Christmas
and
and there was just no job for him. So he
started pounding the pavement just going
office to office to office looking for
work. Finally he found a position in the
PDB staff, the president's daily brief
and the job was to be the briefer for
the lowest ranking official entitled to
a PDB to a president's daily brief.
Right? There are like 16 people who get
the presidential briefing every morning.
This lowest ranking person was the
director of intelligence programs at the
National Security Council and it just
happened to be George Tennant.
And so he John went down to the White
House and he and George immediately hit
it off. They are I I never encountered
two people who were more similar in
personality than John Brennan and George
Tennant. They're both, Forgive me, this
is gonna sound awful. They're both ugly
pockfaced
alpha dogs, you know, cigar smoking,
philandering.
This is just how they are or were. And
George, even though George was only
around 40 years old, he had had a heart
attack recently. And so he wasn't
allowed to smoke. So after the briefing,
every day, John and George would walk
out of the White House to this little
kiosk that used to stand on the corner
of 17th Street and Pennsylvania Avenue,
and they would buy cigars, and they'd
stand there and smoke and laugh and joke
and talk. Well, lo and behold,
George becomes the deputy director of
the CIA in Bill Clinton's second term.
He brings John back with him to the
White House, and names him deputy
director of the office of Near Eastern
and South Asian Analysis, Martha
Kesler's boss.
And the very first thing he does when he
gets back to the office is he fires
Martha Kesler.
So there were some administrative
changes at the time. The director of
intelligence was undergoing a
reorganization and so a more senior
officer squeezed Jon out of that
position. He was only in that job for
about three months. So George Tennant
who saw great things for John Brennan
decided to name John the CIA station
chief in Riad. Now John had never had
five seconds of operational experience
any time in his in his life. and all of
a sudden he's in charge of one of the
biggest and most important stations in
the world.
That is normally a two-year position.
You can ask to extend for a third year.
He extended for a fourth year and a
fifth year and finally came back to
headquarters as the deputy executive
director of the whole CIA, the fourth
ranking official in the entire CIA.
There was a problem in Riad though, and
that is this persistent rumor or
persistent reports that it was John that
ordered that the 911 hijackers be given
visas to enter the United States. I've
always believed that to be true. I don't
have smoking gun evidence that it is
true, but it would not be out of the
ordinary for that to be the case.
Why would you give someone visas who you
know are in al-Qaeda, the this terrorist
group who have been plotting, in fact,
there was this Malaysia summit, I
believe in 2000, that's right,
>> to go into the United States and do this
planes attack to blow up uh these
towers. See, that that sounds crazy to
you and it sounds crazy to me, but if
you are this gung-ho alpha dog who
thinks that he is smarter than everybody
else in the room, you're going to try to
recruit them when they get to the United
States so that you can double them back
against al-Qaeda,
what we used to call core al-Qaeda, um,
bin Laden, Zawahi, and the people
immediately around them. Well, that
makes sense actually because the CIA is
famous for recruiting terrorists. It's
what we do around the world uh in Syria
and Afghanistan, which is where of
course al-Qaeda came from. So that that
kind of tracks with the history of that
organization.
>> Sorry to cut you off.
>> No, no, you are exactly correct.
Uh and then
911 happens. He comes back. He's the
he's the uh the deputy executive
director of the number four. He becomes
the executive director of the number
three person in the agency. It's George
Tennant, John McGlaughlin, and John
Brennan. One, two, and three.
And then he decided that greatness
awaited him. And he wanted to head his
own agency. So he lobbyed President Bush
to create what was briefly called the
TTICK, the Transnational Terrorism
Information Center. It's now called the
National Counterterrorism Center and he
was its founding director as he proudly
says in his official bio. Um I I was the
executive assistant to the CIA's deputy
director for operations at the time. Uh
Jim Pavitt and Jim hated Brennan.
Everybody hated Brennan. And and Jim
used to mock Brennan whenever somebody
would say, "Well, we there's a report
from the tick." He would he would say
from the t
tick
what's the t tick and its eminent
director have to say about an issue and
then everybody would chuckle and you
know the truth is that Brennan was
telling everybody who would listen at
the time that he believed he would be
the next secretary of defense and that
never materialized for him but that's
that's how he saw himself. I mean it was
just a natural that he would become the
director of the CIA. But how did he
become director of the CIA? So in 2007
there was this enormous wave of
retirements at the CIA in the senior
intelligence service um itself. We were
we were six years past 911. People were
exhausted. It was time to cash in and
move on.
Brennan was one of those
by some by some accounts 180 senior
intelligence service officers who
retired in ' 07. But they all saw
themselves as the next Secretary of
Defense, the next Secretary of State,
the next National Security Adviser or
CIA director. All 180 of them,
half of them went to the John McCain
campaign. Half of them went to the
Hillary Clinton campaign. John Brennan
was literally the only one that went to
the Obama campaign
and then Obama won. And Brennan was the
guy. You're probably a little bit too
young to remember that as soon as Obama
won in 2008, he named Brennan CIA
director. And the progressive left went
crazy. They said, "This guy is a Bush
administration murderer.
who was one of the godfathers, one of
the founders of the torture program. And
that's the guy that you want to be CIA
director. And Obama withdrew the
nomination. Well, he made him the deputy
national security adviser for
counterterrorism because that position
doesn't require Senate confirmation. And
the liberals could jump up and down all
they wanted. There was nothing they
could do to stop it. Also, the
calculation was in four years, the
liberals would have forgotten about all
this stuff. And they did,
>> right?
>> They did. And so in 2012, he became the
CIA director.
>> It's really amazing. Um, I want to ask
you, you know, in the course of that
time and and it was pretty much the same
same or similar time span that you were
uh with the CIA. The organization seems
to have gone from representing the
interests of what it was basically
founded to represent, which is the
interests of Wall Street. um and the
seven sisters, the the oil company,
Standard Oil. Um that was at least the
case when someone like George HW Bush
was a CIA director. Um what seems to
have happened at least in the early 90s
beginning then uh is that
>> uh the CIA has morphed into basically a
second branch of MSAD uh basically uh
under the control of Tel Aviv.
Obviously, we have this incredible and
bizarre uh intelligence sharing
arrangement, not at the CIA, but between
the NSA uh and uh Israel sharing raw
signal intelligence with that country
even before our own analysts see it. But
I I think you know a great example that
just happened uh or that just occurred
in the last year was uh the CIA director
now Ratcliffe going to Trump blocking
out Tulsi Gabbard and the other uh more
moderate realist voices uh
non-intervention voices in the
administration to share the MSAD's own
cooked up intelligence on Iran which
ultimately reportedly uh as the gray
zone uh reported convinced the president
to bomb that country in June. So when
did that transition happen where it at
least was it uh the organization was at
least representing you know some
American interests although albeit
corporate interests you know of Wall
Street and and Standard Oil to now just
full-on representing Israel's interests.
How did that happen?
My my career started in January of 1990
and in January of 1990 it was already
that way.
Um I I have told the story many times
that my very first briefing that I ever
gave after being on the job for just six
weeks was to um Mossad and Shinbet
and they actively solicited my
willingness to
cooperate with them more than I
otherwise was allowed to. And I I
indignantly pointed at the guy, the
Mossad representative, and I said, "I am
not recruitable. Don't even think about
it." My boss later laughed and he said,
"They they do that to all of us. All of
us the first time they meet us. It's
like they can't help themselves." Um, so
in January of 1990, it the the
relationship was already that close and
that one-sided. I I can't help but to
think that
that it had to be that way during, you
know, beginning in the Reagan
administration because if it was already
that way during George HW Bush, I mean,
it had to start somewhere and we were
constantly on the brink of armed
conflict with Iran all through the
Reagan administration. So, I'm I'm going
to make a an educated guess and say
that's that's when this enhanced
closeness started. Now, you make a good
point that Tulsi Gabbard and frankly
others of of the anti-war persuasion
have been largely pushed out of this
administration or if not pushed out than
marginalized.
Uh, Ratcliffe
in my estimation appears to be a neocon.
Uh, Marco Ruby is Marco Rubio is a is a
well-known neocon. We've already bombed
Iran at the insistence of the Israelis.
We've now sent two aircraft carrier
battle groups to the Gulf at the
insistence of the Israelis. uh we took
out Saddam Hussein at the insistence of
the Israelis
and all that did was to strengthen the
hand of Iran. I happen to be speaking
with you from Dubai right now and I can
tell you that that government officials
and academics who follow these these you
know issues of international import are
genuinely worried right now about what's
coming next. Uh, I say often in
podcasts, forgive me if I'm repeating
myself, if you really want to know what
American military intentions are, watch
naval movements because if we're not
moving aircraft carrier battle groups,
we're bluffing. Well, we're moving two
aircraft carrier battle groups right
now. And that has me very worried. It
has people here in the Persian Gulf very
worried. And this is exactly what the
neocons want. Lindsey Graham has to be
jumping up and down right now.
>> Yeah, he he absolutely is. And it's
everything that the Israel lobby has
wanted forever. It's amazing, too,
because if you read the National
Security Strategy that was published
less than two months ago, it seems uh or
in November,
it said we're going to get out of the
Middle East. We're no longer going to
interfere to impose our own values on
that region or try to change their forms
of government. we're going to accept
what they have and work with them on,
you know, issues of common interest. Um,
and we're not doing that at all. We're
basically doing exactly what, uh, you
know, President Jeb Bush, um, or a
President Hillary Clinton likely would
have done.
>> You're I think you're exactly right.
Yes,
>> I want to move um to a topic I've been
meaning to ask you about for a while. It
just concerns the anatomy of the CIA
because obviously it's a highly secret
organization. The only information we
get from it is whatever the CIA will
choose to leak to the public uh to its
stenographers and the New York Times or
the Washington Post like David Ignatius
or we'll learn things from uh you know
obituaries of uh various CIA officers um
or in the case of yourself you know
brave leakers who by the way are very
rare. we we don't see them often. Um
that's how we learn anything about the
CIA. So we don't learn much. One of the
I would say uh
most secret uh parts of the CIA is the
uh is a part of the special action
group. It's called the political action
group. Um obviously as I just said these
CIA later leaders and station chiefs are
are generally revealed in their
obituaries and through other reporting
but since the 1980s uh not a single
political action group officer has been
identified to the public. Uh so who led
that uh organization after 1982 and the
exit of Raymond uh or sorry Walter
Raymond Jr. and the ultimate creation of
the NE at the same time uh which is
basically a CIA organization. All of
that is unknown who led the political
action group. So what is that group and
and why is it so secretive even compared
to other branches of the CIA?
>> Yeah. Well,
the the group is essentially the CIA's
lead clandestine um propaganda arm. It's
the It's the group that is able to put
propagandists in place around the world,
keep them funded, and then supply to
them the propaganda to be released. It
used to be called um the active measures
group.
Uh but when the when the Iron Curtain
came down, the the Berlin Wall came
down, uh it changed its name like
everything else did. But you're right.
This is this is the group that would
be working with or would be financing
um NE
uh that would be working with or
financing the Democratic and Republican
National Committee's international
groups. And you run into them every once
in a while overseas. I ran into both of
them in Kuwait.
Uh, and I mean like weeks after the war
ended in 1991, like there wasn't even
any food and half the the country was on
fire, but the DNC and the RNC are there
and they're flush with money.
Um, so,
you know, there was this
there was always this
carefulness
to
not propagandize the American people,
right? They always had to they always
had to ensure that what they were doing
was was outwardly focused. It was
focused on on foreign minds and foreign
voices and foreign you know media
outlets and personalities.
But Barack Obama changed all that uh in
u
what was it 20 the national uh
the National Defense Authorization Act
of 2011 I think is what it was. Yeah.
It's kind of a funny story. The NDAA
uh it was changed for the strangest
reason. We've got these propaganda
outlets aimed at Cuba called Radio T
Radio Marti and TV Marti, right? And we
know I know with 100% certainty because
I did a study on it for the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee. We know
that nobody in Cuba watches TV Marty and
nobody in Cuba listens to Radio Marty.
Sometimes they're jammed, usually not.
The only time that Cubans actually watch
or listen to them is when they're
playing baseball games.
>> They're covering baseball games because
the games are in Spanish.
>> That's it. Well, the Dish Network, you
know, the Dish Network, that satellite
TV company in the US, um, they
picked up radio and TV Marti in the
southwestern corner of Florida to beam
at Cuba.
But there was this little slice of
territory right on the coast of Florida,
like around Fort Myers, where Dish
Network subscribers could get TV
>> Marty.
>> Well, that's illegal. You can't
propagandize the American people. And so
members of Congress wrote a wrote an
amendment
lifting the prohibition on
propagandization of the American people
just so the Dish Network could continue
to carry TV Marti. Well, it had there
was broad fallout from that decision.
Now the CIA can propagandize the
American people. The CIA can plant uh
pro-CIA stories in the American media,
which as you noted a few minutes ago,
they do with their preferred
stenographers at the Post and the Times
and and elsewhere.
And it's perfectly within the confines
of the law. That law should never have
been amended. Never. Because now, even
as Americans, we don't know what's true
and what's false. We don't know what
originated at the CIA uh just to try to
to win our minds.
[clears throat]
[snorts]
>> So, Congress authorized the CIA to
propagandize Americans. That's pretty
amazing. Um I want to move on to another
organization actually that that you're
not a part of, but that you are very
familiar with due to your time in
Afghanistan, which is the DEA. um which
most people really don't think of as
being related at all to the CIA or even
serving some of the same purposes, but
they really seem to when you look at uh
what they do particularly with uh their
involvement with the Afghanistan war uh
which if people remember Afghanistan
during the course of that war became the
global hot spot for heroin production
and poppy production. Uh the DEA would
publish reports during that war saying
that all of the heroin production was
caused by the Taliban, the people who
the CIA and the State Department were
fighting rather than the Northern
Alliance and the various tribes that we
were allied with in the region who it
turns out were actually the ones growing
all the heroin. um including for
instance the uh president Cararzi of
Afghanistan, his brother uh who was on
the CIA payroll. Um and so I guess my
question is what does the DEA's uh
involvement or or all these reports that
they were publishing which we now know
were fake, what does that reveal about
the role of that organization uh and and
just in that deep state network that we
have in the United States and their role
abroad? you know, that's actually that's
actually a more complicated question
than it than might appear on the face of
things. Um, and and I'll start with a
little bit of background. So, many of
your viewers will have seen the uh the
television series Narcos on Netflix. And
one of the themes in Narcos is just as
the DEA is going to move in for the for
the arrest, they're going to grab Pab
Pablo Escobar. They're gonna grab the
gentleman of Cali. Um the the CIA
station chief steps in and just screws
up the whole operation because the CIA
doesn't care about drug interdiction.
They cared about communism or terrorism.
That was always true. and the the CIA
had for the most part a very difficult
contentious relationship with DEA, but
not always because what you just said,
this cooperation, this clandestine
cooperation between the CI CIA and DEA
on drugs is also true.
So when I was the senior investigator on
the Senate Foreign Relations Committee,
I was there from 2009 to uh 2011.
I told John Kerry, who was the chairman
at the time, that I wanted to go to
Afghanistan and do an indepth study on
heroin poppy.
When the Taliban were running the
country in the year before 9/11,
Afghanistan produced literally zero
heroin poppy. None.
There was a fatwa that was issued by the
Taliban forbidding the cultivation of
heroin poppy.
So
by 2009, Afghanistan was producing 93%
of the world's heroin. 93% of all the
heroin in the world was coming from
Afghanistan. So I flew out there and I
told the Pentagon in advance, of course,
that I was coming and that I wanted to
um you know, investigate this and fly
down to the heroin producing areas. They
didn't like that at all. Not at all. So
I I fly into Kabell. There's a
helicopter waiting for me and it takes
me to Bram uh air base. And in Bagram,
they give me this briefing. They're very
formal, the military in their briefings.
And it was funny to me. They thought
that that would satisfy me and I didn't
really need to go actually see heroin
poppy growing. So I said, "Well, let's
go." You know, I I had made plans. I had
expectations that we would go to
Kandahar Province and then to Helman
Province, which is where all that poppy
was growing. They fought me on it, but I
insisted and I outranked them, frankly,
as a as a uh senior congressional staff
member. I had the rank of a brigadier
general, onear general. So, it's the
only time I ever pulled rank ever in my
entire career. And I made them fly me
first to Kandahar
uh and then to Lashgar where we had a
little outpost, a little state
department outpost called a PRT. And
when we got to Lashar,
I insisted that we get in a jeep with
security and a translator and we just
drive into the poppy fields until I
could find a heroin poppy farmer. I
wanted to talk to him. And so sure
enough, we find a poppy farmer out there
cultivating his fields. And we pull up
and he's very nervous. And the
translator says that, you know, I'm from
the from the Congress in Washington and
I wanted to talk to him about Poppy.
Okay. He says, what do you want to know?
And I asked what in retrospect was a
very naive, silly question. I said,
"Why do you grow poppy when instead you
could grow things that have two growing
seasons like onions or pomegranates or
tomatoes?" And he goes like this.
"The Americans told me in 2001 that if I
told them where the Arabs were hiding, I
could grow all the poppy I wanted." And
I said,"What Americans told you you
could grow all the poppy you wanted?" As
soon as that second question came out of
my mouth, my military handler grabbed me
by the collar and said, "We got to go.
We're under threat." And pulled me back
to the jeep and we took off. So, I get
back to Washington
and I write this paper. I bang this
paper out and I include this information
and I secretly send the paper to a
friend of mine at DEA. He was assigned
to this DEA off-site facility way out in
the sticks in Virginia
and he calls me back and he says,
"Buddy, you know you're never going to
get this paper published, right?" And I
said, "Why not?" And he said, "Because
we want them to grow poppy.
It's our poppy." And I said, "Why in the
world would we want to produce 93% of
the world's heroin?" And he said,
"Because almost all of that heroin goes
to Russia and Iran, and we want them to
be addicted to heroin. It weakens their
societies."
And he was right. I never got that paper
published. John Kerry killed it because
the CIA told him to. And now here we are
all these years later where China
produces, you know, 90s something% of
the world's fentinel.
All that fentinel comes to the United
States. Why? Because the Chinese want us
to be addicted to fentinel. It weakens
our society.
But that was one of the most egregious
cases where I saw CIA and DEA working
together in direct opposition
to
the best interests of the United States.
>> I want to move to some current events.
Uh first of all, I I can ask you about
this. There was a really concerning
letter that was published uh by Ron
Weiden and he wrote it to the CIA on
February 4th. It was it was brief so I
could read it to you here. He said,
"Dear Director Ratcliffe, I write to
alert you to a classified letter I sent
you earlier today in which I express
deep concerns about CIA activities."
That was it. That was the whole letter.
I guess my question is if Widen has
these deep concerns about CIA
activities, as he calls it, I think it
would be useful if he told the American
people what exactly those activities
are. He'll never see,
>> you know, Senator Mike Rall, for
instance, famously read
>> zero.
>> Yeah. The Pentagon papers into the uh
congressional record. Those were
classified documents, right?
>> And you're normally not allowed to do
that, but because of the speech and
debate clause that we have in our
constitution, you are. Um, so why
doesn't someone like Widen do the same?
>> He doesn't have the balls to do it. You
know, this is this is a problem that I
have with Widen. If you look at all of
the members of the House and Senate
Intelligence Oversight Committees, Widen
is the only one who will challenge the
agency,
but he will only challenge the agency
using the AY's rules.
Several of us
begged Widen and Stuart Udall
to
under this the speech and debate clause
of the Constitution to read into the
record the Senate torture report and
they just refused. Um, shortly after I
was released from prison back in uh,
2015, I was invited to a dinner at the
Greek ambassador's residence and Widen
was another one of the dinner guests and
he came up to me and said, "Hey, welcome
home." And I said, "Thank you, Senator."
I said, "I got to tell you, I was I was
a little disappointed in you. I thought
you would have done more to uh to help
me." And he says, "Look,
it took all of my energy just to not
lose my security clearance."
And I was like, "Oh, you're afraid of
them.
That's what it is. He'll walk right up
to that line." And God bless him because
he's the only one who will, but he'll
never ever cross it. So, it didn't
surprise me one iota
>> that he didn't either release the first
letter to the to the media
>> or refer to the to the contents of the
first letter in the second letter. Not
surprised at all.
>> Yeah. [snorts] And also, he famously was
the one to ask uh the CIA director at
the time or head of national I forget
his title, but it was John Clapper.
>> Yeah. at the head of DNI uh whether or
not the uh intelligence community was
unconstitutionally spying on Americans
without any warrants. Uh the only reason
he asked that question in the first
place is because it I mean apparently he
knew you wouldn't ask that question uh
if you did not receive some sort of tip.
It was very specific um to what they
were doing which no one at the time
knew. It was Glenn Greenwald and Edward
Snowden who exposed it. Um, but somehow
Widen knew and he kept it secret,
keeping the CIA secrets on their behalf
from the American public, even though he
works for Americans. Uh, it was very
bizarre.
>> Yeah. And then, you know, Clap, what
Clapper could have said was, "Senator,
I'm happy to answer that question in
closed session." It's all he had to say,
>> but he didn't. He said no. And when
later confronted that that one-word
answer, no, was a felony,
uh, it was making a false statement or
also contempt of Congress. He said,
well, no was the was the least incorrect
answer he could think of to give at the
time. And Widen just accepted that.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. No one gets in trouble for
that either, for committing uh that
level of perjury, uh lying about
unconstitutional programs. In fact, the
only people who seem to get in trouble
are the ones who leak uh information
about what our government is doing uh
legally uh behind the backs of Americans
like like you did. Um let me ask you one
final question which is about
uh Iran, what's happening in Iran mainly
and and the Trump administration. It was
reported by the Wall Street Journal,
what really anyone with eyes and ears
could see for themselves over the past
month, that the United States uh has
been very actively involved in trying to
fment these protests in Iran. Uh that
they smuggled in thousands of Starlink
terminals, flooding that country uh with
Israeli propaganda,
>> maybe as many as 40,000 Starlink
terminals.
>> Yeah, it's a really amazing and quite an
operation. Congratulations
uh to the CIA and MSAD on that one. Um
although it so far it's been
unsuccessful. They haven't really uh
turned over that regime. It was reported
earlier that the CIA of course played a
very similar sabotage role in Venezuela
preceding our bombing of that country
and abduction of their uh democratically
elected leader um or you know not so
democratically elected in that case. Um,
in fact, the Trump administration was
was pretty open about how they used CIA
covert action uh in Venezuela, even
announcing that they were working to
destabilize Venezuela as they were doing
it. I'm wondering how you would compare
the ways in which Trump is now using the
CIA to how his predecessors like Obama
used it.
Yeah, this is something that I just
simply don't understand about Donald
Trump and his personal ideology. I was a
I was a vocal believer
in the idea that the MAGA right and the
progressive left could could come
together to oppose wars of choice. I
really believed that was going to be the
future of the of the Republican party
and Donald Trump, you know, for all of
his protestations that he is that he
has, you know, either negotiated peace
or over he has overseen the negotiation
of peace between countries, you know, 7,
8, 11, depending on what countries
you're counting. um he's just been
wholly neocon when it comes to Iran. You
know, one of the reasons why we know
about this is that the Israelis have
told us the Israelis have leaked they
they couldn't help themselves but to
leak
their operations uh to the Israeli
media. Uh we know for example that the
Mossad has been working with the MEK,
the Mujah,
which until Hillary Clinton took them
off the terrorist list was on the
terrorist list. And now Hillary
represents them and and Howard Dean and
Rudy Giuliani and Corey Luwendowski and
big mucky mucks of both parties
representing
a terrorist group that tried to
assassinate the US ambassador in Iran
and the highest ranking American general
in Iran in the 1970s and was allied with
Saddam Hussein until he was overthrown.
So,
we know that the Israelis and the
Americans smuggled in as many as 40,000
Starlink terminals so that people would
be able to maintain their internet
access. We know that the Israelis and
the MEK
were the ones who jinned up these these
protests that led to so many deaths. We
know that the Israelis and the MEK set
fires to at least 16 mosques and then
burned 38 fire trucks so that the fire
trucks weren't available to respond to
the fires.
Um I think this has disaster written all
over it. We started this conversation by
talking about aircraft carrier battle
groups and how there are well there's
the USS uh Abraham Lincoln is in the
Arabian Sea right now and the USS George
HW Bush is steaming now from the coast
of uh Virginia to the Persian Gulf. Um
does Donald Trump really believe that
two aircraft carrier battle groups are
going to overthrow the uh the Iranian
government? You know, there's this very
dangerous belief, it seems, in the
administration that all the Iranians
need is a gentle push and democracy is
going to flourish. It's going to take
root and flourish and we're going to
live happily ever after. And there are
going to be diplomatic relations between
Iran and the US, between Iran and
Israel, and maybe the Sha's son returns,
which he won't, and everybody's going to
be, you know, it's all going to be milk
and honey. And there's no precedent in
the history of the planet Earth for
anyone to conclude that that's how
things are going to go.
So I'm I'm very worried about what the
Israelis and the CIA are doing in Iran.
I think it's incredibly destructive. I
think a lot of people are going to die
if we initiate uh an attempt to
overthrow the government. And one thing
nobody's talking about, how do we defend
aircraft carriers which take like an
entire day just to turn around from a
hypersonic missile when we know that the
Iranians have hyper sonic missiles? You
can't defend against one of those,
especially when you're a ship the size
of an American city.
So, I'm genuinely worried about the way
things are going. I think that we should
be deep in diplomatic negotiations with
the Iranians right now. I think that we
should care one wit what Israeli uh
national interests are here. It should
be what's good for the United States and
we should be using the good offices of
the government of Oman to affect these
uh these talks. And I think that in
order in order for whatever agreement
that's negotiated to stick that the
president has to then send it to the
Senate to be ratified.
It's the only way that we can come out
ahead in this thing.
>> Yeah. Well, I I completely agree. Of
course. Um John, it was it was great to
talk to you. I'm going to be respectful
of your time. Um I hope we could talk
again soon.
>> I [snorts] look forward to that. Thanks
for the invitation.